[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "There is a tremendous gap between youth and the elderly in all of the following EXCEPT",
    "option": [
      "political knowledge.",
      "political participation.",
      "political interest.",
      "volunteering.",
      "media use."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Political knowledge",
    "option": [
      "is greater among youth than the elderly.",
      "fosters political tolerance.",
      "is not that important in a democracy.",
      "is generally high in the United States.",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Voter turnout matters because",
    "option": [
      "federal funds are allocated on the basis of the number of voters in a congressional district.",
      "better candidates are selected when more people vote.",
      "politicians pay more attention to those who vote than to those who do not vote.",
      "it makes citizens feel better.",
      "it makes our country look better."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Government is defined as the",
    "option": [
      "organization that brings problems to the attention of public officials.",
      "body that is concerned with economic problems while leaving social problems to other institutions of society.",
      "agency that implements policies that have been enacted by other institutions of the political system.",
      "executive branch and its agencies.",
      "institutions and processes through which public policies are made for society."
    ],
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The policymaking institutions of the American national government include all of thefollowing EXCEPT",
    "option": [
      "the Supreme Court.",
      "the presidency.",
      "political parties.",
      "Congress.",
      "the Senate."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "One advantage of the Internet for democracy is that it",
    "option": [
      "provides less information than newspapers.",
      "makes it easy to avoid political topics.",
      "makes it easier for citizens to communicate directly with government.",
      "will provide more political information to political elites.",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Things that are indivisible, nonexclusive, and that everyone can share are called",
    "option": [
      "intangible property.",
      "socialized.",
      "community property.",
      "communist.",
      "public goods."
    ],
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Governments in the modern world, whether democratic or not, are similar in doing all of thefollowing EXCEPT",
    "option": [
      "protecting citizens ยน civil liberties.",
      "maintaining a national defense.",
      "providing public goods.",
      "collecting taxes.",
      "providing public services."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "A public good is defined as",
    "option": [
      "something in which any member of society can share.",
      "something provided by the government that cannot be provided by the private sector.",
      "a choice that government makes in response to a political issue.",
      "a public policy that is good for the nation as a whole.",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following statements about public goods is FALSE?",
    "option": [
      "The government usually provides public goods.",
      "Public goods are things that everyone can share.",
      "Individuals have powerful incentives to provide public goods.",
      "Public goods are not profitable.",
      "Public goods are indivisible and nonexclusive."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "All governments",
    "option": [
      "provide public goods and socialize citizens into the political and social system.",
      "ensure safety on the high seas and promote free enterprise.",
      "maintain national parks and a national defense.",
      "guarantee a capitalist economy and collect taxes.",
      "hold elections."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "All governments",
    "option": [
      "have written constitutions.",
      "are elected.",
      "have a legislature.",
      "provide services.",
      "have a president."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which of the following statements about taxes is TRUE?",
    "option": [
      "One out of every three dollars earned by an American citizen is used to pay taxes.",
      "Despite the image presented by the media, survey data reveal that Americans feel they are getting their money's worth for the taxes they pay.",
      "About one-tenth of the average American citizen's salary goes to taxes.",
      "The tax burden in the United States is higher than in most other democratic nations.",
      "All of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "An interest group so single-minded that its members often vote on only one issue, ignoring apolitician's stand on everything else, is known as",
    "option": [
      "a one-issue group.",
      "a uni-issue group.",
      "a hot-button group.",
      "a single-issue group.",
      "a mono-issue group."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "When compared with the rest of the world, America has a relatively low",
    "option": [
      "number of offices up for election.",
      "number of candidates who seek office.",
      "frequency of elections.",
      "voter turnout in elections.",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Many politicians believe that single-issue groups",
    "option": [
      "stimulate the political system to solve public policy problems.",
      "are essential to democracy.",
      "complicate efforts to seek the middle ground on various issues.",
      "play a unifying role in American politics.",
      "do not affect policymaking."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Politics is defined by Harold Lasswell as",
    "option": [
      "conflict in society.",
      "the exercise of power.",
      "the resolution of conflict in a way that serves the public.",
      "who gets what, when, and how.",
      "a course of action to solve a problem."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Single-issue groups",
    "option": [
      "are rapidly losing prominence in American politics.",
      "usually run their own candidates for public office.",
      "have little sympathy for compromising.",
      "help facilitate the construction of a cohesive national public policy.",
      "are highly regarded by political scientists for their contributions to democracy."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which of the following statements best describes voter turnout in the United States?",
    "option": [
      "Among democratic nations, the United States leads the world in voter turnout.",
      "Voter turnout in the United States is constitutionally mandated.",
      "Voters are usually a microcosm of the entire body of American citizens.",
      "Most American voters consider politics as critical to their interests.",
      "The United States has one of the lowest voter turnout rates in the world."
    ],
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The list of problems to which political leaders are paying serious attention is a(n)",
    "option": [
      "problem set.",
      "policy agenda.",
      "issue constellation.",
      "legislative package.",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": 1
  }
]
